Richard Halliburton Papers, 1900-1973: Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Special Collections.
Richard Halliburton Papers
1900-1973
1903-1940
C0247
Princeton University Library. Special Collections. Manuscripts Division One Washington Road Princeton, New Jersey 08544 USA
29.2 linear feet 61 archival boxes
Halliburton, Richard, 1900-1939.
Richard Halliburton traveled extensively in the first part of twentieth century after graduating from Princeton University in 1921. The collection contains autograph and typescript drafts of seven of Halliburton's books, short stories, essays, school notes, and other travel memorabilia, as well as Halliburton's correspondence with his parents and others, research materials about Rupert Brooke, and a significant group of photographs documenting his travels throughout Europe, Africa, Asia, and the Middle East.
Richard Halliburton was an American traveler, adventurer, and author, whose books about his exploits captured the romantic spirit of his generation. He followed Ulysses' route through the Mediterranean and emulated Lord Byron by swimming the Hellespont. He swam the Panama Canal, ran from Marathon to Athens, visited the penal colony at Devil's Island, and climbed the Matterhorn, Mount Olympus, and Mount Fuji. These and other experiences became the basis for Halliburton's romantic narratives; and his literary career developed out of his meticulous logging of events that occurred on his adventures. However, in March 1939, Halliburton left Hong Kong aboard a motor-powered Chinese junk called the "Sea Dragon", which he had built, en route to San Francisco. Both he and his boat disappeared after encountering a severe typhoon, some 1,200 miles west of Midway Island.
The papers span Halliburton's short but adventurous life, from his Lawrenceville School essay, "Disillusioned," through his Princeton University years (Princeton Class of 1921), his years of worldwide travel, lecturing, and writing, to his posthumously-published "autobiography" of letters to his parents (1940). Autograph and/or typescript drafts of seven of his books, The Royal Road to Romance (1925), The Glorious Adventure (1927), New Worlds to Conquer (1929), The Flying Carpet (1932), Seven League Boots (1935), A Book of Marvels (1937), and Second Book of Marvels (1938), are present, as are some short stories, essays, and notes from his school days. There are also passports, publishing contracts, memorabilia, maps, and newspapers clippings. Halliburton's numerous letters to his parents (1919-1939) provide a vivid account of his travels, and they are supplemented by a large quanitity of photographic prints and negatives documenting the locations he visited, many of which were never published in his books. Correspondence of others includes letters from Devil's Island prisoners, with some manuscripts. Also present are Halliburton's research materials for a biography of Rupert Brooke that he never wrote, including his correspondence with Brooke's friends and acquaintances and summaries of interviews he had with them, as well as copies of Brooke's works and correspondence, some clippings, and photographs.
The collection is arranged into the following five series: Works; Correspondence; Biographical Materials; Photographs; and Papers of Others.
Collection is open for research use.
Original film-based photographic negatives (Boxes 35-39) are stored offsite in cold storage at the ReCAP facility. Please consult with the Special Collections about having this portion of the collection recalled to Firestone Library for your use. This process normally requires 48-72 hours notice.
Papers of Halliburton are a gift of Wesley Halliburton. Collection of letters and telegrams from Halliburton to his editor is a gift of Thomas Orchard. Photographs are a gift of William C. Wilson. Misc. manuscripts, documents, correspondence are a gift of the First National Bank of Memphis. 3 Letters from Halliburton to P.L. Williams were purchased in 2005. An inscribed copy of The Royal Road to Romance was a gift of Patricia A. Oakes in 2017.
No appraisal information is available.
Publications: All of Halliburton's books were published by Bobbs-Merrill of Indianapolis: The Royal Road to Romance (1925), The Glorious Adventure (1927), New Worlds to Conquer (1929), The Flying Carpet (1932), Seven League Boots (1935), A Book of Marvels (1937), Second Book of Marvels (1938), Richard Halliburton: His Story of His Life's Adventures (1940).
Halliburton, Richard, 1900-1939.; Brooke, Rupert, 1887-1915.; France. Armée de terre. Légion etrangère -- Photographs.; Adventure and adventurers -- 20th century.; Authors and publishers -- United States -- 20th century.; Fathers and sons -- United States -- 20th century.; Prisoners' writings, French -- French Guiana -- Devil's Island -- 20th century.; Schools, Russian -- Photographs.; Seri Indians -- Photographs.; Students -- Soviet Union -- Photographs.; Travelers -- Maps.; Travelers, American -- 20th century.; Voyages and travels -- 20th century.; Voyages around the world -- 20th century.; Angkor (city) -- Photographs.; Athens (Greece) -- Photographs.; Athos (Greece) -- Photographs.; Baalbek (Lebanon) -- Photographs.; Bagdad (Iraq) -- Photographs.; Bali (Indonesia) -- Photographs.; Borneo (Malaya) -- Photographs.; Boulder Dam (Colo.) -- Photographs.; Corfu Island (Greece) -- Photographs.; Dardanelles -- Photographs.; Devil's Island (French Guiana) -- Photographs.; Egypt -- Photographs.; Ethiopia -- Photographs.; Fort Jefferson (Fla.) -- Photographs.; Gibraltor -- Photographs.; Greece -- Photographs.; Iguazu Falls (Brazil) -- Photographs.; Iran -- Photographs.; Istanbul (Turkey) -- Photographs.; Ithakē (Greece) -- Photographs.; Java (Indonesia) -- Photographs.; Jerusalem (Israel) -- Photographs.; Kasmir (India) -- Photographs.; Ladakh (India) -- Photographs.; Leh (India) -- Photographs.; Macchu Picchu (Peru) -- Photographs.; Manila (Philippines) -- Photographs.; Morocco -- Photographs.; Moscow (R.S.F.S.R.) -- Photographs.; Olympus, Mount (Greece) -- Photographs.; Petra (Jordan) -- Photographs.; Saint Petersburg (Russia) -- Photographs.; San Salvador -- Photographs.; Taj Mahal (Agra, India) -- Photographs.; Taorima (Sicily) -- Photographs.; Tempe (Greece) -- Photographs.; Thailand -- Photographs.; Tiberias Lake (Israel) -- Photographs.; Timbuctoo (Mali) -- Photographs.; Vladivostok (Russia) -- Photographs.; Contracts.; Correspondence.; Drafts (preliminary versions); Maps.; Photographs -- 20th century.; American history/20th century; American literature; Travel
- Series 1: Works, 1917-1940; 19 boxes
  Arranged into three subseries by genre.
  This series contains writings by Richard Halliburton, including books, such as Complete Book of Marvels and The Flying Carpet, articles and short works, such as "The Elephants and the Alps" and "Experiments in Assination," and some early works.
  - Subseries 1A: Books, 1917 March 14-1940; 17 boxes
    Arranged alphabetically by title of work.
    This subseries contains drafts and related materials for Richard Halliburton's published books. Photographs from Halliburton's travels documented in his books can be found in Series 4: Photographs.
    - Complete Book of Marvels, undated; 1 box
      - Dear Reader, undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Chapters 1-30, undated; 30 folders (Folder 2-31)
      - Copybooks 1-5, undated; 5 folders (Folder 32-36)
    - The Flying Carpet, 1930-1931; 3 boxes
      - Final Contents: Chapter Titles, undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Chapters 1-33, undated; 33 folders (Folder 2-34)
      - Copybooks 1-14, 1931; 14 folders (Folder 1-14)
      - Flying Carpet Logbooks, 1931; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - List of French Military Words and Foreign Legion Affairs, 1930; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Le Centieme Anniversaire de L'Heroique Legion Etrangere, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - 2 Legionnaire Programmes, 1931; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - "Shepard Life in Palestine", undated; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - "Hitherto Many People Have Written About the French Foreign Legion", undated; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - "Unknown", by Sig___X, undated; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Bromide Paper, 2 plates, undated; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - The Glorious Adventure, undated; 2 boxes
      - Chapters 1-12, undated; 14 folders (Folder 1-14)
      - Chapters 13-20, undated; 9 folders (Folder 1-9)
      - Copybook: Lecture Notes on The Glorious Adventure and Other Stories, undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
      - List of Places Where The Glorious Adventure was Sindicated, undated; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - New Worlds to Conquer, undated; 3 boxes
      - Prologue, undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Chapters 1-33, undated; 33 folders (Folder 2-34)
      - Copybooks 1-4, undated; 4 folders (Folder 35-38)
      - Copybooks 5-18, undated; 14 folders (Folder 1-14)
      - Copybooks 19-21, undated; 3 folders (Folder 1-3)
      - Devil's Island Works by Prisoners, undated; 28 folders (Folder 4-31)
    - Richard Halliburton: His Story of His Life's Adventures, 1940; 2 boxes
      - Table of Contents, undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Publisher's Note, undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Chapters 1-17, undated; 17 folders (Folder 3-19)
      - Chapters 18-21, undated; 4 folders (Folder 1-4)
      - First Complete Galley, 1940; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - The Royal Road to Romance, 1919-1927; 2 boxes
      - Chapters 1-37, undated; 37 folders (Folder 1-37)
      - Miscellaneous, 1919-1922; 2 folders (Folder 38-39)
      - Promotional Materials, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 40)
      - The Royal Road to Romance Inscribed Copy, 1925-1926 February 17; AM 2017-90; 1 folder
        Hardback copy of The Royal Road to Romance (Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1925), inscribed by Richard Halliburton on February 17, 1926, to Miss Clara Engel on a photograph of Halliburton in Athens, which is affixed to the title page. A two-page letter from Halliburton to Engels, written on Hotel Bristol (New York) stationary, is pasted in at the end of the book.
    - Second Book of Marvels, undated; 1 box
      - Chapters 1-30, undated; 30 folders (Folder 1-30)
      - Corrections of Chapters 13 and 14 by E. Evans, undated; 1 folder (Folder 31)
      - Copybook, undated; 1 folder (Folder 32)
    - Seven League Boots, 1917 March 14; 3 boxes
      - Introduction, undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Chapters 1-34, undated; 34 folders (Folder 2-35)
      - Copybooks 1-14, undated; 14 folders (Folder 1-14)
      - Copybooks 15-19, undated; 5 folders (Folder 1-5)
      - Galley Sheets, undated; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - "The Massacre of the Romanovs", undated; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - "I Killed the Czar", undated; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - Radio Halifaxus for Tribune NY; Regarding Tsar Nicholas, undated; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      - News Release, "On 1917 March 14, Tsar Nicholas II...", 1 folder (Folder 10)
      - "The Last Days of the Romanovs", undated; 1 folder (Folder 11)
      - Miscellaneous Romanov Material, undated; 1 folder (Folder 12)
  - Subseries 1B: Articles and Short Works, 1926; 37 folders
    This subseries contains drafts and related materials for Richard Halliburton's articles and other short writings.
    - Cairo Guide, undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Dutch and London Follies, undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - The Elephants and the Alps, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Experiments in Assination, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - For Swimmers Only, undated; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - The Glorious Adventure, undated; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    - Hints to Travelers - 250 BC, undated; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    - How to Swim the Hellespont on a Can of Sardines, 1926; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - Idyll from the Indes, undated; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - Jerusalem's Greatest Secret, undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    - Jerusalem - The Holiest of Cities, undated; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - The Lady of Delight, undated; 1 folder (Folder 12)
    - Little Journeys Through Java, undated; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    - The Luxor Circus, undated; 1 folder (Folder 14)
    - Midwinter Dueling with Fujiyana, undated; 1 folder (Folder 15)
    - Missolonghi and Skyros, undated; 1 folder (Folder 16)
    - New Turkey - The Wonder Country, undated; 1 folder (Folder 17)
    - The Oasis of the Oracle, undated; 1 folder (Folder 18)
    - On to Siberia, undated; 1 folder (Folder 19)
    - Otto and Ophelia, undated; 1 folder (Folder 20)
    - The Pageant of Peking, undated; 1 folder (Folder 21)
    - Persian Princesses (The Three Princesses), undated; 1 folder (Folder 22)
    - The Place Where the Sun is Tied, undated; 1 folder (Folder 23)
    - The Prince of Bagdad, undated; 1 folder (Folder 24)
    - Rambling Down the Rhine, undated; 1 folder (Folder 25)
    - Richard Halliburton Answers his Critics, undated; 1 folder (Folder 26)
    - Robinson Crusoe - Who was he and Where was his Island, undated; 1 folder (Folder 27)
    - The Singular Siamese, undated; 1 folder (Folder 28)
    - "...Sinking the Merrimac", undated; 1 folder (Folder 29)
    - Tiburons, undated; 1 folder (Folder 30)
    - Toledo, undated; 1 folder (Folder 31)
    - The Two Slaves, undated; 1 folder (Folder 32)
    - The Well of Death, undated; 1 folder (Folder 33)
    - Where did Columbus Discover America? Where was he Buried?, undated; 1 folder (Folder 34)
    - Where I'll Spend my Honeymoons, undated; 1 folder (Folder 35)
    - Without Lawrence in Arabia, undated; 1 folder (Folder 36)
    - The Wonders of the World I Want my Son to See, undated; 1 folder (Folder 37)
  - Subseries 1C: Early and Unidentified Works, 1917-1920; 20 folders
    Not arranged according to any arrangement scheme.
    This subseries contains drafts and related materials for Richard Halliburton's early and unidentified writings.
    - "Disillusioned", undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - The Lawrence "1917 Class Ode", 1 folder (Folder 1a)
    - Leaflet Invitation to the Sundowners of the Sagebrush, undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - "Three Days", 1919 March 18; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - "Drifting", 1919 May; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - The Vagabond, 1920; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - Ruskin: Apostle of Nature, undated; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    - Memories of a New York State Prison Inmate, undated; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    - Far Away Children, undated; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - Tragedie's Child, undated; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - The Happy Hunting Ground, undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    - Byron the Inspiring, undated; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - Class Notes on Victorian Literature, undated; 1 folder (Folder 12)
    - Class Notes and Outline: English 402, Literary History of American Ideals, undated; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    - French Exercises and Notes, undated; 1 folder (Folder 14)
    - Van Dyke's English Poetry Notes, undated; 1 folder (Folder 15)
    - Art Notes, undated; 1 folder (Folder 16)
    - Copybook, Unidentified. "New Tales From Arabia", undated; 1 folder (Folder 17)
    - Unidentified Notes, undated; 1 folder (Folder 18)
    - Fathers: Unidentified Speech, undated; 1 folder (Folder 19)
- Series 2: Correspondence, 1900-1946; 7 boxes (1 partial)
  Arranged into four file groups by type of correspondence.
  This series contains the correspondence of Richard Halliburton with his parents during his travels, correspondence with prisoners on Devil's Island, correspondence regarding Rupert Brooke, as well as some miscellaneous letters.
  - Letters to His Parents, Wesley and Nelle Halliburton, 1919-1939; 3 boxes
    - Halliburton, Richard, to his Parents, 1919-1925; AM 17588, AM 12478; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      5 early telegrams. 1 ALS to his parents in which he discusses his life at Princeton. Partial ALS to his parents from Greece in 1925 (2 pages). Found in papers of Wesley Halliburton of Rhodes College, November 9th, 1984.
    - Halliburton, Richard, to his Parents, 1928; AM 17588; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      45 ALSs, 197 pages. 9 telegrams.
    - Halliburton, Richard, to his Parents, 1929; AM 17588; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      34 ALSs, 114 pages. 1 telegram.
    - Halliburton, Richard, to his Parents, 1930; AM 17588; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      41 ALSs, 150 pages. 8 telegrams.
    - Halliburton, Richard, to his Parents, 1931; AM 17588; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      34 ALSs, 138 pages. 1 telegram.
    - Halliburton, Richard, to his Parents, 1925; AM 17588; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      26 ALSs, 98 pages.
    - Halliburton, Richard, to his Parents, 1926; AM 17588; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      39 ALSs, 167 pages.
    - Halliburton, Richard, to his Parents, 1927; AM 17588; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      37 ALSs. 197 pages.
    - Halliburton, Richard, to his Parents, 1932; AM 17588; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      33 ALSs. 152 pages.
    - Halliburton, Richard, to his Parents, 1933; AM 17588; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      42 ALSs. 187 pages.
    - Halliburton, Richard, to his Parents, 1934; AM 17588; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      48 ALSs. 186 pages.
    - Halliburton, Richard, to his Parents, 1935; AM 17588; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      40 ALSs. 140 pages.
    - Halliburton, Richard, to his Parents, 1936; AM 17588; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      47 ALSs. 179 pages.
    - Halliburton, Richard, to his Parents, 1937; AM 17588; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      46 ALSs. 161 pages.
    - Halliburton, Richard, to his Parents, 1938; AM 17588; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      43 ALSs. 164 pages.
    - Halliburton, Richard, to his Parents, 1939; AM 17588; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      7 ALSs. 13 pages.
  - Devil's Island Correspondence, 1929-1939 June; 1 box
    - Eugene, Louise Margot, 1929 January 1; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - Zoutfoy, Armour, 1929 June 9; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - Mave, Yvonne, 1939 June 30; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Du Fresnoy, Jr., 1929 July 16; 3 folders (Folder 4-6)
    - DuFresnoy, Margot, and Georges, Jr., undated; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    - S. Marie, 1929 July 21; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - A. Guillerm M., 1929 July 8-1929 August 20; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - Haulard, Leonice, 1929 August 21; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    - Paul, 1929 August 22; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - Jean Romain, Louise, 1929 September 17; 1 folder (Folder 12)
    - Haulard, Leonce, 1929 September 19; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    - Jean Romain, Fernand, 1929 September 20; 1 folder (Folder 14)
    - Abrio, Josephine, 1929 September 20; 1 folder (Folder 15)
    - Paul, 1929 September 20; 1 folder (Folder 16)
    - Feifuetz, Emile, 1929 September 21; 1 folder (Folder 17)
    - Jean Romain, L., 1929 September 22; 1 folder (Folder 18)
    - Glassburg, John A., M.D., 1929 October 7; 1 folder (Folder 19)
    - Feifuetz, Emile, 1929 October 18; 1 folder (Folder 20)
    - Paul, 1929 October 18; 1 folder (Folder 21)
    - Bellenoit, Rene (Julet Chayent), 1929 October 19; 1 folder (Folder 22)
    - Jean Romain, L., 1929 October 30; 1 folder (Folder 23)
    - Haulard, Leonce, 1929 November 18; 1 folder (Folder 24)
    - Haulard, Leonce, 1929 December 4; 1 folder (Folder 25)
    - Belburoitz, 1929 December 10; 1 folder (Folder 26)
    - Qeiling, Henry Max, 1929 December 20; 1 folder (Folder 27)
    - Fiquet, Emile, 1930 January 2; 1 folder (Folder 28)
    - Van Rompaey, Leon, 1930 January 7; 1 folder (Folder 29)
    - Haulard, Leonce, and Paul, 1930 April 28; 1 folder (Folder 30)
    - Haulard, Leonce, 1930 June 23; 1 folder (Folder 31)
    - D., Paul, 1930 April; 1 folder (Folder 32)
    - Haulard, Leonce, 1930 December 10; 1 folder (Folder 33)
    - Farey, Marcel, 1931 February 5; 1 folder (Folder 34)
    - Van Rompaey, Leon, 1930 April 2; 1 folder (Folder 35)
    - Sarawak, Sylvia A., 1932 Spring; 1 folder (Folder 36)
    - Bonamy, L., 1933 December 8; 1 folder (Folder 37)
    - Enveloples: To Leon van Rampaey and Lucien Caillol, undated; 1 folder (Folder 38)
    - To Felicia Duprat Jean from Rue Eliegentrae, undated; 1 folder (Folder 39)
    - Duprat, Jean, undated; 1 folder (Folder 40)
    - Cedenkenis van uwen Zoon en Broeder Leon, undated; 1 folder (Folder 41)
    - Signet, Messr. E., undated; 1 folder (Folder 42)
    - Envelope and note, 1929; 1 folder (Folder 43)
    - [Belbenoit], Rene, undated; 1 folder (Folder 44)
    - Note to Leonce Haulard, undated; 1 folder (Folder 45)
    - Wick, Jean (Publisher), to Darvin, Tom, Regarding Prisoners' Works, 1933 October 22; 1 folder (Folder 46)
  - Letters Regarding Rupert Brooke, 1912-1946; 2 boxes (1 partial)
    - By Richard Halliburton, 1927; portions of 2 boxes
      - Abercrombie, Lescelles, undated; 1 folder (Folder 47)
      - Asquith, Arthur, undated; 1 folder (Folder 48)
      - Baynes, F.G., undated; 1 folder (Folder 49)
      - Bonham-Carter, Lady Violet Asquith, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 50)
      - Brooke, Mrs., undated; 1 folder (Folder 51)
      - Brooke, Justin, undated; 1 folder (Folder 52)
      - Brown, Maurice, undated; 1 folder (Folder 53)
      - Cornford, Mrs., 1927; 1 folder (Folder 54)
      - de la Mare, Colin, undated; 1 folder (Folder 55)
      - de la Mare, Walter, undated; 1 folder (Folder 56)
      - Dent, E.J., Professor, undated; 1 folder (Folder 57)
      - Doty, G.L., undated; 1 folder (Folder 58)
      - Drinkwater, John, undated; 1 folder (Folder 59)
      - Flakins, W.B., undated; 1 folder (Folder 60)
      - Forster, Arnold, Mrs., 1927; 1 folder (Folder 61)
      - Foster, Rev. H.C., undated; 1 folder (Folder 62)
      - Freyberg, Bernard, Colonel, undated; 1 folder (Folder 63)
      - Grant-Watson, E.L., undated; 1 folder (Folder 64)
      - Hartley, General, undated; 1 folder (Folder 65)
      - Hubback, Eva, undated; 1 folder (Folder 66)
      - Kelly, J. Mary, undated; 1 folder (Folder 67)
      - Keynes, Geoffrey, Dr., 1927; 1 folder (Folder 68)
      - Knox, Ronald, Father, undated; 1 folder (Folder 69)
      - Lindsay, Gertrude, undated; 1 folder (Folder 70)
      - Lucas, St. John, undated; 1 folder (Folder 71)
      - Macauley, Rose, undated; 1 folder (Folder 72)
      - Mansel, Muriel L., undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Marsh, Edward, undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Masefield, John, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Miles, Colonel J. Wardlaw, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - Nesbitt, Cathleen, undated; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Nevinson, H.W., undated; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Pye, Sybil, undated; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Richards, Noel Olivier, Mrs., undated; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - Salter, Helen, undated; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      - Strachey, James, undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
      - Ward, Dudley, undated; 1 folder (Folder 11)
      - Waugh, Alec, undated; 1 folder (Folder 12)
      - Williams, Iolo, undated; 1 folder (Folder 13)
      - Wilson, Lady, undated; 1 folder (Folder 14)
      - Woolf, Virginia, undated; 1 folder (Folder 15)
    - To Richard Halliburton, 1912-1946; 51 folders
      - Abercrombie, Lascelles, undated; 1 folder (Folder 16)
      - Baynes, F.G., 1927; 1 folder (Folder 17)
      - Bonham-Carter, Lady Violet Asquith, 1927-1928; 1 folder (Folder 18)
      - Brooke, M. R., Mrs., 1925-1927; 1 folder (Folder 19)
      - Button, Bill, undated; 1 folder (Folder 20)
      - Carmichael, D.E.G., 1936; 1 folder (Folder 21)
      - Clark, Howard, 1929; 1 folder (Folder 22)
      - Clemens, Cyril, 1936; 1 folder (Folder 23)
      - Cornford, Frances C. (Darwin), 1927; 1 folder (Folder 24)
      - Dalton, Hugh, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 25)
      - de la Mare, Colin, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 26)
      - de la Mare, Walter John, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 27)
      - Dent, Edward J., 1927; 1 folder (Folder 28)
      - Doty, George L., 1927; 1 folder (Folder 29)
      - Drinkwater, John, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 30)
      - Forster, K. Arnold, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 31)
      - Foster, Henry C., 1927; 1 folder (Folder 32)
      - Fry, Geoffrey, undated; 1 folder (Folder 33)
      - Gibson, Wilfred Wilson, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 34)
      - Greene, Alexander, 1933; 1 folder (Folder 35)
      - Greenham, Kelly, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 36)